Cactus 1549.
Runway four. Cleared for takeoff.
Cactus 1549. Cleared for takeoff.
Sync & corrections by Blue-Bird™
Fixed & Synced by bozxphd
Modify by Blue-Bird™
(subscene.com/u/1191276)
Mayday, mayday. Cactus 1549.
We've lost both engines. Both engines.
No relight on one or two.
Cactus 1549,
if we can get it for you,
do you wanna try to land runway 1-3?
Departure control, we can make it.
We're turning back towards LaGuardia.
LaGuardia Tower, Cactus 1549,
trying to make 1-3.
Sully, we're too low.
Sully, we're too low!
Come on.
Just a little farther.
Sully!
Lorrie, I love you.
What the hell's the matter with you?
The onboard count, 150 passengers,
three flight attendants
and two pilots, one of whom,
the senior pilot, drew on
all of his experience and skill,
which combined with
near-miraculous good luck
and a result that was,
frankly, astounding.
There were some non-critical injuries,
but everyone, everyone, survived.
The first pictures
of US Airways Flight 1549 reveal...
You think that you're gonna die.
That's what you think.
And then, miraculously, you don't.
Thank you, Captain.
Thank you, thank you.
Okay, thank you,
everybody, thank you.
Thank you, Captain Sullenberger,
for being here today.
We also wanna welcome
First Officer Skiles.
I'm glad you could make it in
this morning.
Not as glad as we are.
For the record,
we had an Aircraft Systems Team
on this investigation.
Also Aircraft Structures, MRT,
Aircraft Performance, ATC,
Wildlife Factors, Survival Factors
and Emergency Response.
Today, we begin with our operation
and human performance investigation
on the crash of US Airways Flight 1549.
- Water landing.
- Captain?
This was not a crash
and it wasn't a ditching.
We knew what we were
trying to execute here.
It was not a...
It was not a crash.
It was a forced water landing.
Why didn't you attempt
to return to LaGuardia?
There simply was not enough altitude.
The Hudson was the only place
that was long enough and smooth enough
and wide enough to even attempt
to land the airplane safely.
Air Traffic testified
that you stated
you were returning to LaGuardia,
but you did not.
As I began the left turn,
I realized I couldn't make it back
and it would have eliminated
all the other options.
Returning to LaGuardia
would have been a mistake.
Okay, well, let's get into how you
calculated all those parameters.
There was no time for calculating.
I had to rely on my experience
of managing the altitude and speed
of thousands of flights over four decades.
You're saying you didn't do any...
I eyeballed it.
You eyeballed it?
Yes.
The best chance those passengers had
was on that river.
And I'd bet my life on it.
In fact, I did.
And I would do it again.
Aviation engineers are theorizing
you had enough energy
to make it back to a runway.
Well, engineers are not pilots.
They're wrong.
And they weren't there.
Regardless, we have to follow up
on all implications
as part of our investigation.
Our computers will run
return scenario algorithms.
It'll generate simulations
with your exact parameters.
The dual engine loss, the altitude.
Everything you faced
when you made your decision.
I would like to oversee
those computer simulations.
Not possible during an investigation.
You stated that it was
a dual engine failure
due to multiple bird strikes?
That would be unprecedented.
Well, everything is unprecedented
until it happens for the first time.
How much sleep did you get
the night before?
Eight hours. Enough.
Is it possible your blood sugar was low?
I was rested, alert
and completely aware of my surroundings.
When was your last drink,
Captain Sullenberger?
Nine days ago.
Drugs?
No. Never.
First Officer Skiles?
Uh, don't drink. Never have.
Captain, have you had
any troubles at home lately?
No more than anyone else.
And nothing that affected my work.
It's bullshit.
Why are they looking for something
we did wrong when it all turned out right?
It didn't turn out all right
for the airline
and their insurance company.
We should expect some blowback.
Come on, Mike. What are they gonna say?
That he shouldn't have saved everybody?
It's not personal.
NTSB's just doing its job.
Once they have all the facts,
it'll calm down.
Sully,
they should pin on the medal
and send you back to work.
Sorry. This mailbox is full.
I didn't call Lorrie since this morning.
Apparently everyone else did.
Not meaning to bother, but I have to say,
it is an honor driving you today.
Thank you.
What has it been this year so far?
Bernie Madoff, two wars without end.
Many million new people with no work.
And that's just the first
two weeks of January.
Friday's headline? This is beautiful.
Hey, Mike. How about we add
the driver as a character witness?
Finally!
Yeah, finally.
The NTSB had us tied up all day.
I know.
I just needed to hear your voice.
I've been hearing everybody else's.
You'd be amazed how many cousins you have.
It doesn't feel much like family here.
Pretty quiet here, too.
The reporters want me to give an update
inside the mind of Sully.
What should I tell them?
Lorrie, tell them you're not
allowed to talk to anybody.
- Look, I can't hear you.
- Lorrie, I...
- I can't hear you. Call me back.
- I'm trying to tell you
you do not have to talk to anybody.
I can't hear you. Call me back.
Lorrie, I'm trying to tell...
Hey, Captain Sully!
- Captain Sully!
- Sully!
How does it feel to be a miracle maker?
Sully, one question!
- How did you pull off the impossible?
- Sully!
Captain Sully! Sully!
Pardon me.
Captain Sully!
I'm thinking about
running over the press with the car.
Self-defense.
You think a jury would convict?
Just do what you have to do.
You know, I'm taking that as permission.
The cops'll be coming after you.
Sullenberger couldn't be here.
He is not able to speak to the media
while the NTSB
is conducting its investigation.
Sully, are you listening to me?
Maybe we should talk later.
Honey, it is later.
I've been waiting all day.
Are you okay?
Yeah, just tired, that's all.
How are the girls?
Well, they're...
They're a little overwhelmed.
It sounds like you are, too.
Yeah...
Yeah, well, they'll be all right.
It is a lot.
Yes, it is.
Those missing engines
were definitely not
what investigators wanted...
The whole world is talking about you.
My Sully.
God, I just can't believe this.
Lorrie, I have to stay here longer
for the NTSB investigation.
Did I tell you that already?
I apologize if I didn't tell you.
There is no need for you to apologize.
You are right where you need to be.
I want you to know,
I did the best I could.
Of course you did. You saved everyone.
Uh, maybe we should
just talk in the morning. I'm tired.
I'm overwhelmed by all this attention.
I'm gonna be on TV in the morning.
What are they gonna ask me?
What am I gonna say?
Sully, do you want me to come be with you?
No, Lorrie.
Thanks, but the girls need you.
Tell them I love them.
I love you. Get some sleep.
Yeah.
Hey, maybe when I wake up,
it'll be January 14th.
Wouldn't that be good?
I love you.
Why Captain Sullenberger
made that fateful decision
to turn the Hudson into a runway?
Well, only he can answer.
But we now know it was the wrong choice.
A choice that endangered the lives
of all of those onboard.
So, while much of the country
hails him as a hero,
this new information will certainly
change everyone's understanding
of the so-called "Miracle on the Hudson."
Sully Sullenberger,
are you a hero or a fraud?
- Hello?
- Jeff?
I'm sorry to call so late.
It's okay.
There's no sleep in this room either.
Can you believe they charge
$5 for a Snickers?
I could bankrupt the airline
in about four bites.
Just thought
maybe you would want to, uh...
Talk?
Absolutely.
Let's get some air.
Great.
All right. Be down there in five minutes.
You enjoying the shakes?
The nightmares, rapid heartbeat.
A little bit.
Union's offering us counseling.
Yeah. What are they gonna say?
"You were in a plane crash and lived.
"It may have a minor impact
on your day-to-day."
I don't like not being
in control of the process.
- I want my self back.
- Yeah.
I'm hoping six months from now,
we'll just be laughing
about how we got to meet David Letterman.
We're doing David Letterman?
Yeah. Right after the next NTSB interview.
Letterman.
I'm guessing Dave
is gonna be slightly funnier.
This is so surreal.
I guess I'm having a little trouble
separating reality
from whatever the hell this is.
Yeah.
This is two men freezing their asses off.
Sully.
Don't worry. You did a great thing.
It's gonna be remembered
for a very long time.
Here's the funny thing.
I've delivered a million passengers
over 40 years in the air,
but in the end,
I'm gonna be judged on 208 seconds.
Come on. Tomorrow's gonna be a good day.
Computer sims will prove you were right.
We can all put our wings back on.
You wanna run?
Yeah, let's run.
Fucking cold out here.
It was obvious.
It was a critical situation,
losing thrust in both engines
at a low altitude
over one of the most densely
populated areas of the planet.
But choosing to land on the Hudson,
that was still a big "if."
I was sure I could do it.
You were?
Yes.
How do you feel
when people call you a hero?
I don't feel like a hero.
I'm just a man who was doing his job.
The right man for the job
at the right time.
You've been flying for what,
nearly 40 years?
Forty-two. It's been my life.
My whole life.
Your aircraft.
My aircraft.
I'll be busy crop dusting
in the Super Cub rest of the summer.
So, you can take the plane up, I guess,
when you please.
Still six bucks an hour.
I'll consider it lesson time.
A pilot never stops acquiring knowledge.
You'll make mistakes, everyone does.
Just learn from them.
Yes, sir.
And never forget,
no matter what's happening,
to fly the airplane.
Absolutely, sir.
Oh, one other thing,
and this is important.
- Sir?
- You can go ahead and smile.
All right.
- I apologize for the perspiration.
- Oh, no.
After what you did,
I'd think that Katie
couldn't be too intimidating.
Oh, it wasn't Katie.
It was the lights and the camera
that she brought with her.
Okay. All done.
That was from my mom.
Her name is Brenda,
she says to say "thank you"
and that she's single.
Well, you tell Brenda thank you,
but I've got a girl at home.
- Lucky woman.
- Thank you.
Sully.
Sully. Sully!
Sully, where are you?
I'm standing here calling your name.
What's up with you?
You need to get focused.
Because the media request
avalanche continues.
Yeah. Yeah.
Larry Rooney volunteered to jump in
and ride shotgun with you
the rest of the way.
Thought you might need a friend.
He'll take you to today's NTSB meeting.
Airbus completed their
computer simulations as well.
Good. Good, that'll help.
There's something else.
Arnie Gentile called.
He has the ACARS data.
The left engine
was still operating at idle.
Not possible. I felt it go.
It was like we were stopped in midair.
Arnie said there was a chance
it was sub-idle,
that it still could've had thrust.
I'm just letting you know
since the NTSB already does.
Hmm.
Is retirement next?
What's next for you? What's next?
Some room, please.
Sully! Over here!
Hey, Larry. Good to see a friendly face.
Might be the last one you see today.
You've got to be kidding me.
We've been through all this before.
Look,
I'm sorry if you're frustrated,
but our job is to investigate
how a plane ended up in the Hudson River.
On the Hudson River.
Isn't it a little early in the year
to go fishing?
Seeking the facts
is hardly "fishing," Mr. Skiles.
Okay,
then here's the most important fact.
There's only two people who know
what happened in the cockpit that day
and I'm one of them.
And we appreciate your perspective.
Why do you even think we're here today?
It's because Captain Sullenberger
did not head back to LaGuardia.
Look, I just finished training on the A320
and I can tell you,
the only reason the plane operated
as well as it did,
that the aircraft could land anywhere,
is because Captain Sullenberger
turned on the Auxiliary Power Unit.
He was simply following the QRH.
No. No, he wasn't.
He wasn't following
proper procedure at all.
And I know, because
I had the QRH in my hands.
He switched on the APU immediately
after engine rollback.
According to Airbus,
that's the 15th thing on the list to do.
Fifteenth.
If he had followed the damn rules,
we'd all be dead.
Maybe that's the part you don't like.
You're not used to having
answers to your guesses.
Look, what Jeff is saying
is that I know the A320,
what it does and what it doesn't do.
I have read countless CVR transcripts
of deceased pilots
and I have significant
accident investigation experience.
There is no question
that you are a talented, dedicated,
experienced professional.
But all the flights you piloted
before January 15th
and every crash you investigated
are not the purview of this investigation.
Only US Airways 1549 matters today.
Your union has been advised.
ACARS data relayed that the left engine
continued to turn throughout the flight.
Then the ACARS data is wrong.
The evidence shows that the left engine
was at idle or sub-idle
immediately following the bird strike.
You show me the left engine,
I'll show you dead birds and no power.
The left engine was lost in the crash
due to excessive damage on touchdown.
But we can circle back to that later.
Let's just assume that it was,
as you say,
a dual engine loss due to bird strike.
Your weight was 151,510 pounds,
wind and temperature
north, northwest, 21°.
Speed and altitude
200 knots at 2,818 feet.
- Agree?
- Correct.
We were able to run
all the algorithms concurrently.
And the resulting computer simulations
of US Airways Flight 1549
show that the aviation engineers
were correct.
There was enough altitude and speed
after the bird strike
for a successful return to LaGuardia.
Successful?
The plane landed at LaGuardia.
Intact.
Undamaged.
You got that from one computer simulation?
No.
From 20.
Including attempts made for
Teterboro runways 1-9
and LaGuardia runways 2-2 and 1-3.
Every computer simulation
with the exact flight parameters
demonstrated that a return
to LaGuardia was possible.
And not just possible, probable.
Does anyone need to hear
further computer evidence?
Captain Sullenberger?
First Officer Skiles?
Not at this time.
I would like to go over
the parameters that were used.
We will make them available to the union.
Thank you.
Once the investigation is complete,
we'll be able to share
the actual computer simulations.
For now, they remain confidential.
We cannot afford a leak to the press.
There's been far too much talk
in the press already.
When the complete cockpit
voice recording is compiled,
along with ATC
and all onboard transcripts combined,
we will call you back.
Thank you, gentlemen. Good day.
Thank you.
They're playing Pacman.
You were flying a plane
full of human beings.
Somehow, that's not how I remember it.
It just doesn't seem right.
It's because it's not right.
Sully, you did everything you could
and it was more than enough.
Ask the passengers.
Ask your wife and kids. Ask mine.
So what was the first thing
you heard from the cockpit?
- "Brace for impact." Yes.
- "Brace for impact."
Now, uh, ever hear that before
coming out of a cockpit?
No, not ever.
Um...
Ever hear that in any other
aspect of your lives?
I don't know.
They could take this show away from me.
Jeff was relaxed and funny.
He should be getting
all of our interview requests.
Are they paying you
for all this media stuff at least?
It's news, Lorr.
No payment is necessary.
Oh, I wish the bank felt the same way.
Why? What do you mean?
It's just...
We got another notice
about the space in Butte County.
We'll find a tenant.
It just takes time.
Yeah, you've been saying that
for nine months, Sully.
It's still vacant.
The economy has to take a turn.
It feels like if we lose that space,
the next domino to fall is the house.
Lorr, we're not gonna lose the house.
I'm sorry.
I'm just anxious
and I'm alone and not enough sleep.
Yeah, I know.
Not a lot of sleep going on here either.
I'm sorry if I'm adding to your stress.
But just tell me
you'll be back in the air soon.
Not until the NTSB
is finished with their investigation.
We need you flying.
Lorr, if this goes badly,
my career as a safety expert
will end as a website and a business card.
I'm more worried
about your career as a pilot.
What if I did blow this?
What are you saying?
What if I did get this wrong,
so close to the end of my career?
If I endangered the lives
of all those passengers?
Sully, watch the news. You're a hero.
Everyone's gonna have to get used to it,
including the NTSB.
Worst case scenario,
the NTSB lists me as the probable cause.
That's immediate retirement. No pension.
My life's work gone.
Okay, you're scaring me now, Sully.
What is going on?
The left engine might have
still been idling.
And the Airbus simulations say
I could've made it back
to LaGuardia safely.
But that doesn't make sense.
Doesn't jibe with everything
I felt in the cockpit.
Then why did you do it, Sully?
What, land in the water?
Wasn't that the most dangerous thing
you could have done?
Good afternoon, Gursimran.
The, uh, tuna basil
or the ham and cheddar?
Tuna basil, Mr. Sully. Very fresh.
- Thank you.
- Be careful up there.
Too cold today. Too much cold.
When are you gonna come fly with me?
When US Air starts flights to Hyderabad.
I will talk to the chairman,
see what we can work out.
- Oh, for heaven's sakes, Diane!
- No!
- It's his birthday!
- Come on! No, Mom!
Just a little something.
The suitcase is already overstuffed
with gifts for Will.
It's always fun to get
something from the airport.
Feels like you've traveled, too.
Ma, he's turning one.
Don't think he'll be discerning
what gift came from where.
But I will.
Maybe a snow globe.
Something he'll remember.
Something "New York."
Were you this generous when we were kids?
Okay, sweetheart.
I'll get you a snow globe, too.
Fine. Come on.
- Good afternoon, Sheila.
- Captain.
- Hello, Donna.
- Jeff.
- Hey, Sully. How are ya?
Hey, guys! Jeff!
We're not gonna make it!
I've been waiting for a year
for this trip, Dad.
I'm not gonna miss this flight.
Just meet us at the gate, okay?
We'll see you there, Uncle Robbie.
Altimeter is verified. 3-0-2-3.
3-0-2-3.
Start checklist complete.
You really think they'll release us?
I've checked the latest reports.
We're clear all the way to Charlotte.
Then steaks.
Del Frisco's. On me.
Never been.
And I hear good things.
Oh.
The rib eye'll break your heart.
I'm more of a porterhouse man.
The porterhouse will stop your heart.
We are now closed
for US Airways flight 1549,
service to Charlotte...
Wait, wait!
- You got it.
- Wait, wait, wait!
Hi. I'm sorry.
Um, Spirit sent us.
We got canceled and they said
that we were re-routed.
That you guys had some seats?
Flight is closed.
Wait, see that old guy
limping up right there?
That's my dad. It's an emergency.
He's gotta be on this flight.
What kind of emergency?
- Golf emergency.
- This flight canceled?
Oughta be.
- ID's please.
- Oh, my God!
How many people are traveling?
Three. Thank you.
Nothing together.
That's all right.
Hell, I'll fly on the wing.
Here we go.
22A,
6A
And 6C.
- Thank you. Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
- Yes! What!
- Happy ending.
- She gave me the eye.
- You charming bastard!
- Ahoy.
- Welcome aboard.
- How's it going?
- Lucky you made it.
- Yeah, no kidding.
- All right.
- Thank you. Sorry.
- Thank you!
- We're in six, Jeff.
- Oh, no. That's all Jimmy.
I was up till 3:00.
I gotta get some sleep.
You can sleep here.
Not with you verbally running
the course the whole time.
"I think I'll play
the seven iron on the 9th."
No. Good night.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Here. There you go.
- Thanks.
- Yeah, of course.
Hey, guys, I'm in here.
I'm so sorry.
He likes to throw everything.
That's perfect.
I like to catch everything.
Hey, little man.
I googled you last night.
Read all about your company
on your website.
It's impressive.
Thanks.
I thought I was
a good bullshitter, but you?
You could go pro.
Hey.
Oh, I'm only teasing.
The site does make it sound
like your air safety consulting business
has got about 100 employees
and headquarters in three states.
Then when I dug a little deeper,
I realized it's only you.
Go easy.
I'm just getting it going.
I'm not usually accused
of being a bullshitter.
Don't get me wrong.
Actually, it's a compliment.
Off that website? I'd hire you.
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome onboard US Airways Flight 1549
with service to Charlotte.
Please review the safety instruction card
in the seatback pocket in front of you.
It explains the safety features
of this aircraft
as well as the location and operation
of the exit and flotation devices.
Your seat cushion serves
as a flotation device.
LaGuardia ramp, Cactus 1549.
Ready for pushback at gate 21.
Cactus 1549, gate 21 cleared to push.
Spot 28, ground for taxi.
Be sure you turn that off.
Tray table up.
Just once I'd like to
get out of LaGuardia on time.
Well, you know the only way to
Yeah, what's that?
Fly out of JFK.
Funny.
Takeoff minimum fuel quantity verify.
19, 000 pounds required.
We got 21.8 onboard.
19,000 pounds required. 21.8 onboard.
Cactus 1549.
Runway 4. Cleared for takeoff.
Cactus 1549. Cleared for takeoff.
TO/GA.
TO/GA set.
Positive rate.
Gear up, please.
Gear up.
Nice view of the Hudson.
I'll never get over
how beautiful it is up here.
Life's easier in the air.
I guess it is.
Birds!
Whoa.
Oh, shit.
Oh, yeah.
It's just turbulence, probably.
I'll check the cabin.
What do you think's going on?
It's okay.
Everyone, might be a good idea
just to keep your seat belts on.
We got one rolling back.
We have both of them rolling back.
Ignition start.
Oh, my God.
I'm starting the APU.
Just double-check your seat belts, please.
Seat belt. Relax.
Can I make sure
your seatbelts are fastened?
Make sure
your seat belts are fastened.
Seat belts.
- What do you think that was?
- I think it was a bird strike.
- Then we're going back to LaGuardia.
- Yeah.
Get out the QRH.
Loss of thrust on both engines.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
This is Cactus 1549.
We hit birds.
Maintain 1-5000, Delta 3-3-1.
We've lost thrust on both engines.
We are turning back towards LaGuardia.
Okay, you need to return to LaGuardia?
- Turn left heading 2-2-0.
- 2-2-0.
Which engine did you lose?
Both. Both engines.
- Supe?
- Yeah?
I have an emergency.
What's the report?
Both engines.
- What?
- Both engines gone. No thrust.
All right.
LaGuardia says go to runway 1-3.
Tower, stop your departure.
Got an emergency returning.
1549, bird strike.
He lost both engines.
Returning immediately.
Which engine?
He lost thrust in both engines, he said.
Cactus 1549, if we can get it for you,
do you wanna try to land runway 1 -3?
We are unable.
We may end up in the Hudson.
I got an A320 diving for the river.
Al, stack all the inbounds to LaGuardia.
Let's put a hold on the tower, please.
Come on, guys, stay on point.
What about over to our right?
Anything in New Jersey? Maybe Teterboro?
T eterboro tower, I need a runway.
Cactus 1549 needs to go
to the airport right now.
Newark tower, what have you got?
You have runway 2-9 cleared and ready.
- You need emergency landing?
- Yes.
Okay, yeah.
Off your right side is Teterboro airport.
Shit.
This is the Captain.
Brace for impact.
Oh, my God.
What?
Brace, brace, brace!
Heads down, stay down!
Cactus 1549, turn right 2-8-0.
You can land runway one Teterboro.
We can't make it.
We're gonna end up in the Hudson.
I'm sorry. Say again, Cactus?
Cactus 1549, radar contact lost.
KC, come on over here.
You also got Newark off your two o'clock
in about seven miles.
Don't go in the river.
- Sir?
- Plug in.
Cactus 1549, if you can,
you got runway 2-9 available at Newark.
It'll be two o'clock in seven miles.
Come on.
Please, God.
I'm sorry, Patrick.
He's inbound to Newark, I know it.
He just went off the box to focus.
Patty.
He'll come back up.
He's heading to Teterboro.
We need other eyes and ears.
Attention, all aircraft
in the vicinity of the GW.
When we come up
around this bend up here,
we'll see the USS Intrepid.
We got an A320 on emergency descent.
Cactus 1549 is low level above the Hudson.
This is helicopter 1-6-7, Mike Tango.
I've got eyes on him.
Okay. I got a chopper with visuals.
I'm staying on this.
He's out there.
He's headed to Newark, seven miles.
It's only seven miles.
Cactus 1549, this is departure control.
On guard, do you read?
He's going down.
Cactus 1549, do you read me?
Shit! He's going down!
He's gonna hit the water.
- KC, take his seat.
- Sure.
Tester's gonna come down.
Breathalyzer, urine samples,
it's standard.
His voice was so calm.
When he said the Hudson,
I didn't believe it.
This isn't happening.
People don't survive
water landings, Henry.
Pull up. Pull up.
We're gonna brace.
Pull up! Pull up!
Thirty.
Twenty.
Ten.
I'd better go.
I am so sorry. I love you.
Yeah. I gotta go.
It had just taken off
from New York's LaGuardia Airport,
bound for Charlotte, North Carolina,
and then a mid-air disaster
struck US Airways Flight 1549.
It's possible that birds flew into
both of the aircraft engines.
The pilot quickly realized he could not
return to the airport and land.
His options severely limited,
the only place he could go down
was the Hudson River.
Choosing to land
on the Hudson, that was a big "if."
Have you had
any troubles at home lately?
Why'd you do it, Sully?
Land in the water?
Sully, you did everything
you could. It was more than enough.
Every computer simulation
demonstrated that a return was possible.
The left engine
was still operating at idle.
There was enough altitude and speed
for a successful return to LaGuardia.
Wasn't that the most
dangerous thing you could have done?
This is Tasty 1-1.
Abort test bombing run.
I have an emergency
flight control malfunction.
Two, join on me.
Roger that.
Two joining on you.
- Feels like hydraulics.
- Sir, do we need to punch out?
No, I can still fly.
I'm running a control test.
Get the checklist.
We have the checklist, sir.
Increasing thrust.
We need altitude.
Hold on, we 're gonna climb.
Nellis Tower, this is Tasty 1-1
with an emergency
flight control malfunction.
We need a straight-in approach.
Roger, Tasty 1-1.
Turn left 2-0-0 to runway 3.
Unable.
I repeat, I need a straight-in approach.
Okay.
Proceed straight ahead to runway 2-1.
2-1, Tasty 1-1.
Two, I'm decreasing speed.
Clear the board for a damage check.
One, you look clean and dry,
but you're still trailing smoke.
Roger that, Two.
Approach runway 2-1.
One, I'll maintain chase
and follow you in.
I have visual on the runway.
What's our heading?
Heading 0-2-0.
Five miles out, sir.
All right. Gear in three.
Tasty 1-1, check air speed.
Looks like you're coming in hot.
Nellis Tower,
I need speed to maintain control.
Avoiding a stall.
One, check your heading.
You're not gonna make the runway.
I got it.
I'm bringing her back.
That was a hell of a landing, sir.
I didn't think we were gonna make it.
I'm gonna start charging you
for this stuff, all right?
- Oh, get out of here.
- You hear me?
- Thanks, Pete.
You got any nuts?
- Hey.
Let me know if you need anything.
But what still seems so hard to believe
is that everyone
aboard the plane survived,
including two shivering babies
who were found in a life raft...
Hey...
Is that you?
- Are you the pilot? Sully?
- Yeah.
- That is you, right?
Hey, it's a pleasure to meet you.
That was unreal,
what you did the other day.
- That was really something.
- Yeah, he's a hero.
A real pleasure to meet you.
You know, we invented a drink after you
as soon as that happened.
Ain't that right, Johnny?
Yeah, you did. In fact, I'll take one.
The Sully!
It's a shot of Grey Goose
with a, uh, splash of water.
Splash of water.
Hey, listen.
To January 15th.
Best day of the year.
- To Sully.
- Sully.
Hey, Pete.
Sully's here, and he's there!
Damn, Pete. He's everywhere!
Yeah!
Sully!
You're like a real hero, man.
You know that?
Keep it coming, Paulie.
I'll see you on One.
Agreed.
Twenty-one people onboard, Cap.
Last report says
there's ice out by the GW.
- All right, thanks. Roger that.
- All right.
Twenty-one on the TJ,
departing Midtown, slip Seven.
Unbelievable.
I cannot believe
you have the sack to say that.
That's literally like giving
the entire city the finger.
I'll say it again.
Dennis Eckersley is without question
the greatest relief pitcher
in the history of baseball.
Are you blinded by the leg kick?
Is that what it is? Or is it the mustache?
You're just jealous he was never a Yankee.
Jealous?
Yeah.
Now, let's turn to page seven...
Brace, brace, brace!
Heads down, stay down!
Let me hold him.
- Brace, brace, brace!
- It's okay. Let me hold him.
Okay.
Heads down, stay down!
Brace, brace, brace!
- We're not gonna make it, Uncle Robbie.
- It's okay.
Brace, brace, brace!
I love you, Mom.
- Heads down, stay down!
- To the moon and the stars
- and all the way back.
- And all the way back.
Heads down, stay down!
What do we do, darling?
Oh, my God.
Evacuate.
Grab your life vests, please.
Opening forward door.
It's flooding back here!
Rob Kolodjay!
- Dad!
- Go, go, go!
Everyone! The aft exits are unusable.
Move forward to the overwing exits!
And don life vests now!
Go! Exit! Go, go!
Move forward.
Move forward to the right
or left exit door.
Jeff!
He's back there, can you see him?
Dad!
- Everyone, come forward.
- Jump!
Sir, evacuate the plane right now! Go!
Sheila, the raft didn't deploy.
Sir! Come back, sir!
Calm down. You'll be fine.
The rafts are waiting.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hurry up!
It's gonna be bitter out there.
Here you go.
Here. Gonna be bitter out there.
Slowly.
You need to get off this plane now.
Feet first.
Slide slowly and gently.
- Plenty of room.
- Come on, people.
Okay. It's good now. Jump! Jump!
Oh, my God. Is that gas?
We have to jump.
No, no, no, wait!
You seeing this?
Yeah. Holy Christ, that's a plane.
Deploy that
man overboard ladder right away.
All right, I'm on it.
Shit.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
Coast Guard sector New York,
channel 1 -6, Thomas Jefferson.
We have a passenger airliner
in the north river.
We're en route. We will advise.
Let's go, let's go!
Jimmy, Jeff's still on that plane!
We can't leave him there!
Robbie, Robbie. Robbie!
Robbie! The crew will grab him, okay?
- The crew will get him, okay?
- He's in there!
He'll be okay. He'll be okay.
I'm okay, Mom. I'm okay.
- Ma!
- Just leave me.
Keep moving forward!
Follow your instructions.
- It's all right.
- There's water in the back.
- We're doing fine.
- Come on. Let's get out!
One after another. Keep moving forward.
Keep moving forward.
This way. I'll help you out.
You go ahead, sweetheart.
Come on. She can't move.
- Sir! Can you come help us?
- Yes, ma'am?
Right there.
Here's a floatation device.
Take that.
Everyone, keep moving forward.
Over the wings.
If you have a life vest, put it on!
All series near the Intrepid,
plane down.
We got passengers on the wings.
Approach with caution.
Stay calm and you'll all get out.
Thank you.
Move forward, move forward.
Come on!
Put a blanket on her leg.
She needs a tourniquet.
You're gonna be fine, honey. Go slow.
Go slowly. Blanket.
Wrap this around her leg. Make it tight.
It's so cold out here.
Get those first-aid kits
up to the bow
and get some extra life jackets out there.
We're here! We're here!
It's all right. We're here.
Give me a countdown, Victor.
All right.
Three,
two...
We're good. We're good.
Come on, buddy.
Hold it right there, baby. Come on.
Easy. Go easy.
Come on. One at a time.
We're gonna get everybody, guys.
This is Yogi Berra.
We're 30 seconds out.
With a water temperature of 36 degrees
and a wind chill of minus 5,
the surviving passengers of Flight 1549
literally have minutes to live.
We're five out.
We have visual on aircraft.
All right, give me your hand.
If anybody's got any problems,
just wait down there.
We got some really good people
coming on their way, all right?
Stand by.
Fifty yards, go!
You okay?
I got you. You're gonna be okay.
All right?
Got you.
Is anyone still here? Come forward.
Captain! Come back!
Come forward!
We need to get off the plane now.
Captain!
Captain! We have to go!
It's time to get off the plane, right now!
All right, you guys go. Go.
I'll be right behind you.
Sully, we gotta go.
Thank you.
Everybody's okay.
Help is on the way.
Twenty-six passengers
going to Port Imperial.
Nineteen headed to Pier 81.
We got 24 passengers onboard
headed to Port Imperial.
Whoever has miraculously survived
this plummet from the skies
into the icy Hudson
has about 300 of New York's finest
ready to help them.
The only question remaining
is will it be too late?
In Manhattan, Bobby Cuza, New York One.
Come on, sir. Give me your hand.
Grab on.
Give me your hand, sir. It's okay.
We got you.
- My hands.
- Gotta warm them up.
Get him a blanket, fast.
I was sure I was gonna die.
Hey, no one dies today.
Give me your hand.
Here you go, Captain. This way.
Give us your hand, sir.
Sully, wrap it around your arms.
- Climb out now.
- Give me your hand.
Can we get
a couple more blankets over here?
Thank you.
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
Give him some room.
You're welcome.
Hello?
I wanted to call to say I'm okay.
Oh, good. Are you still on the 5:50 home?
There's been an incident.
I'm okay, not a scratch somehow.
Turn on the television.
What do you mean "Turn on the television"?
Lorrie, I can't talk right now.
I will call you from the pier
when things quiet down.
I had to land in the Hudson.
Sully, I don't understand.
I love you, and I'm okay.
Tell the girls I am okay.
But I have to go.
Girls, turn on the TV.
An extensive rescue effort is underway
after a US Airways Flight
crashes into the Hudson River,
- sending passengers scrambling for safety.
- Oh, my God.
If you have any wet clothing on,
take it off
and wrap up in a blanket
from the Red Cross.
You're gonna be okay. Okay, Lucille?
I'm gonna take you right
to the ambulance, all right?
Maybe he's here.
Maybe he beat us somehow.
There's lots of boats! Jeff!
Sully!
Dan!
Dan, I need to know who's hurt
and how badly, and I need a count.
155, that's my number.
That's passengers and crew.
Okay. How are you?
I'll answer that question
when we've counted 155.
All right.
Honey, it's me.
Sort of. I won't be home tonight.
Sherri, I cannot believe
I am talking to you.
Captain. I'm here to escort you
to meet with Mayor Bloomberg
and Police Commissioner Raymond Kelly.
If the Mayor wants to say hello,
he'll have to come down here.
We're still working.
Sully, I can keep assembling the count.
Jeff.
Jeff, I need a count.
We've gotta have a count.
There's no way to get
a real count out here, Sully.
Sully, Jeff's right.
Let's get you in some dry clothes
before you freeze to death.
Captain, what if the Mayor and Chief Kelly
come down here to meet with you?
Dan, because it was a domestic flight...
Yeah, we got no manifest.
We're gonna have to track
the passenger information down one by one.
- Can you help?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna call John Carey.
We're gonna get you a count.
But, Sully, listen. You've done enough.
Let me take it from here.
- Jeff?
- Pop!
- Oh!
- I'm okay.
I was on the other wing.
They brought us to Jersey.
I couldn't see you. I couldn't find you.
I could hear you shouting
my name the whole time.
I shouted back. I guess the river...
Are you okay?
I love you, son.
I love you, too.
Can you believe we made it?
I mean, the plane crashed
on the river!
Are you kidding me?
Ah, so unbelievable.
I've never been so happy
to be in New York in my life.
Hey, Patty.
Supe sent me looking for you.
Everyone's going nuts up top.
- Aren't you coming?
- I guess you didn't hear.
I lost Cactus 1549 in the Hudson.
Huh. I guess you haven't heard.
He landed the son of a bitch!
What?
Everyone's been pulled off.
It's a miracle!
I thought I lost them all.
- They've got to get a TV in here.
- Yeah. Seriously.
What is my pulse rate?
It's 110.
My normal resting is 55.
110...
That's not good.
You are right. 110 is not good.
After what you just went through,
110 is extraordinary.
How is Doreen?
Fairly severe laceration.
But we'll keep her a day or two
to stem the infection.
But she'll be okay?
She'll have a scar
and a hell of a story to tell.
Although no one'll believe her.
Hell, I'm standing here with you right now
and I don't believe it.
You landed a plane on the Hudson.
Not a scratch on you.
Arnie.
The union is pulling out
all the big guns today, huh?
Talked to Dan Britt, Sully.
Got a count.
155.
It's official.
- 155.
155.
Thank you, Arnie.
- Hey, Carl.
- Jeff.
- Sully.
- Carl.
Hell of a thing you pulled off
out there today.
Well, we're here.
It's about all I know at the moment.
Oh, this is Ms. May, with the hotel.
Wanted to have a quick word with you.
I won't take your time, gentlemen.
This is only to say that my staff and I
are committed to protecting your privacy.
So, if there's anything I can do at all...
If it's possible, I'd love to have
my uniform dry-cleaned overnight.
It's the only clothing that I have.
Dry-cleaning?
If it's too much... If it's too late...
Are you kidding?
Captain Sullenberger,
I'd give you this whole hotel if I could.
Oh, okay.
Well, thank you, Evelyn.
Thank you very much.
- Anything for Sully.
- Okay.
Have a blessed day.
What just happened?
You just got hugged by a total stranger.
Ah, come on, Sully.
When's the last time you heard of someone
landing a jet plane on the water
and everybody lived?
Exactly.
I got shaving cream,
razor blades, toothpaste.
And new clothes.
What, did you think we were ninjas?
Kmart was the only store open.
It's Queens. It's 10:00 in the evening.
- You find a Brooks Brothers.
- Yeah.
Sully.
What are you even still doing in uniform?
Ah. You know, I don't know.
Look, guys. It's been a long day.
Why don't you get some rest?
Mike Cleary will be over in the a.m.
and make sure you're both doing okay.
- Thank you, Carl.
- Yeah, thank you, Captain.
It's been a while since
New York had news this good.
Especially with an airplane in it.
I'll see you later, Sully.
The word city officials
keep repeating is "timing."
The perfect timing of the NYPD scuba units
and of the ferry boat captains,
and of course, the inexplicably
precise timing of the pilot.
Captain "Sully" Sullenberger,
who, with almost no time,
became a man for all time.
This is Kristine Johnson...
The ti mi ng.
Reporting live from the Hudson River.
New York One Minute.
The coast guard released this new video
of Flight 1549
making its emergency landing
on the Hudson.
Meanwhile, the search is launched
for the engine of the aircraft.
Hey, Sully. Let me...
Come on. Answer.
Answer!
Larry, the CVR is in two days.
How fast can you arrange a favor?
Sully?
I know that Airbus has simulations
scheduled for the S22 sim at the factory.
But that's next week in Toulouse.
Can you get them to reschedule?
It's 1:30 in the morning.
I need you to make it happen
before we listen to the CVR.
Before our testimony is complete.
Why?
I have a right to see the simulations
and I have a feeling that
with human pilots and not a computer,
the results are going to be different.
What if they show the exact same result?
If they do,
then I'll hand you my wings myself.
It's all about the timing, Larry.
You can accomplish anything
if you're never in a hurry.
I sure as hell agree with that.
The CVR is on Wednesday. That's 36 hours.
Can you make it happen?
I'll try.
It's a lot of phone calls to make.
It's already 7:30
in the morning in France,
so you better get started.
Thank you, Larry. Thank you.
Hey, Lorrie.
Hi. I'm sorry to bother you
before the hearing.
Sweetheart, what happened?
I realized just now,
for the first time, that there were...
There were 155 people
on that plane and you were one of them.
We almost lost you.
Yeah, but you didn't. I'm right here.
How are you holding up?
Oh, I'm holding up.
Please tell me this is almost over.
It's almost over.
Okay.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I'll call you when they're done with me.
- Sully.
- Let's go, Larry.
- Good morning, Sully.
- Jeff.
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome.
My name is Charles Porter.
I've been assigned by the
National Transportation Safety Board
to conduct this public hearing here today.
We have a lot of material to cover.
But before we listen to
the cockpit voice recording...
And we will be listening to it
for the first time
along with you, gentlemen.
Per the request of
Captain Sullenberger and the union,
Airbus has agreed to link us via satellite
to today's piloted simulations.
Upload link, please.
They're just simulations, Sully.
Won't change my mind
about what happened up there.
Might change theirs.
Birds.
Number one's rolling back. And number two.
Auto pilot's off.
- Pilot off.
- Flight Director's off.
Flight Director is off.
All right. LaGuardia, Cactus 1549,
dual engine failure.
We have to return to the field.
Okay. I'm gonna left turn
back to LaGuardia 1 -3.
I'll activate the approach for you.
It's activated.
Runway 1-3.
Glide slopes coming in nicely.
- Flaps two.
Sink Rate 900.
Too low, flaps.
Flight slow.
Forty, 30, 20...
Successful landing
at LaGuardia, runway 1-3.
For the record,
the pilots and the computer
sims bear the same result.
Let's try for T eterboro now, please.
Upload the second run.
Birds.
Give me a heading 3-1-0.
Heading 3-1-0.
I'm gonna give you direct to Teterboro.
Direct Teterboro.
One thousand.
Flaps two.
Too low, terrain.
Fifty, 40, 30, 20...
Successful landing
at Teterboro, runway 1-9.
Multiple airports, runways,
two successful landings.
We are simply mimicking
what the computer already told us.
A lot of toes were stepped on
in order to set this up for today.
And frankly, I really don't know
what you gentlemen plan to gain by it.
Can we get serious now?
Captain?
We've all heard about
the computer simulations
and now we are watching actual sims.
But I can't quite believe
you still have not taken
into account the human factor.
Human piloted simulations
showed that you could
make it back to the airport.
No, they don't.
These pilots were not behaving
like human beings,
like people who are experiencing this
for the first time.
Well, they may not be reacting
like you did.
Immediately after the bird strike
they are turning back for the airport.
Just as in the computer sims, correct?
That is correct.
They obviously knew the turn
and exactly what heading to fly.
They did not run a check.
They did not switch on the APU.
They had all the same
parameters that you faced.
No one warned us.
No one said,
"You are going to lose both engines
"at a lower altitude
than any jet in history.
"But be cool.
"Just make a left turn for LaGuardia
"like you're going back
to pick up the milk."
This was dual engine loss at 2,800 feet
followed by an immediate water landing
with 155 souls onboard.
No one has ever trained
for an incident like that.
No one.
The Teterboro landing,
with its unrealistic bank angle
we were not the Thunderbirds up there.
I'd like to know how many times
the pilot practiced that maneuver
before he actually pulled it off.
I'm not questioning the pilots.
They're good pilots.
But they've clearly been instructed
to head for the airport
immediately after the bird strike.
You've allowed no time for analysis
or decision-making.
In these simulations, you've taken
all of the humanity out of the cockpit.
How much time did the pilots
spend planning for this event?
For these simulations?
You are looking for human error.
Then make it human.
This wasn't a video game.
It was life and death.
Sully's right. That's worth a few seconds.
Please ask how many
practice runs they had.
Seventeen.
Seventeen?
The pilot who landed at Teterboro
had 17 practice attempts
before the simulation we just witnessed.
Your reaction decision time
will be set at 35 seconds.
Thirty-five seconds.
That's not enough time.
We only had 208 seconds total,
so I'll take it.
Upload the link.
Return to LaGuardia.
Now with an added
35-second delay in response time.
- Birds.
- Okay, I saw them.
- Give me 35 seconds.
- Thirty-five seconds.
Time's up.
Here we go.
Flight path vector.
Going for 1 -3.
Okay.
Activate confirm.
All right. You are confirmed.
We're heading right for the airport.
Caution, obstacle.
We're about
seven miles from the runway.
Caution, obstacle.
Terrain, terrain.
Pull up.
Too low, terrain.
We got a little extra speed.
You want some flaps?
Too low, terrain.
No, leave the flaps up.
Fifty, 40, 30, 20...
Let's try T eterboro.
Upload the link, please.
Birds.
Auto pilot off.
Flight Director off.
Hack the time.
- Thirty-five seconds.
Engine one and two fail.
Turn.
Okay.
Let's see if we can make it.
Heading sub 2-9-8.
You seeing Teterboro out there?
I do.
Way too low.
Obstacle, obstacle.
Pull up.
Not gonna work, not gonna work.
Does anyone need to see more simulations?
Now that we've seen
what could have happened,
can we, uh, listen to what actually did?
We will look at all
the results at a later date.
Elizabeth.
For the record,
this is the CVR of US Airways Flight 1549,
January 15th, 2009.
Gentlemen, headsets.
Birds!
Shit.
Oh, yeah.
We got one rolling back.
We have both of them rolling back.
Ignition start.
I'm starting the APU.
- My aircraft.
- Your aircraft.
Get out the QRH.
Priority left.
Loss of thrust on both engines.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
This is Cactus 1549.
Hit birds.
We've lost thrust on both engines.
We are turning back towards LaGuardia.
Okay, you need to return to LaGuardia?
- Turn left heading 2-2-0.
- 2-2-0.
- Which engine did you lose?
- Both. Both engines.
"If fuel remaining, engine mode,
select your ignition."
- Ignition.
- Thrust levers, confirm idle.
- Idle.
Airspeed. Optimum relight, 300 knots.
- We don't have that.
- No, we don't.
Cactus 1549,
if we can get it for you,
do you wanna try to land runway 1-3?
We are unable.
We may end up in the Hudson.
Emergency electrical power,
emergency generator not online.
Online.
ATC notified. Squawk 7700.
Distress message transmit. We did that.
Cactus 1549,
it's gonna be left traffic, runway 3-1.
Unable.
Okay. What do you need to land?
Wind shear.
FAC 1 off, then on.
Been 10 seconds, Captain. Come on.
Talk to me.
Cactus 1549,
runway 4's available if you wanna make
left traffic to runway 4.
I don't think we can make any runway.
Uh, what about over to our right?
Anything in New Jersey? Maybe T eterboro?
Okay, yeah.
Off your right side is Teterboro airport.
LaGuardia Departure,
got an emergency inbound.
This is Teterboro tower. Go ahead.
Cactus 1549 over the GW Bridge.
Needs to go to the airport right now.
Check. Does he need assistance?
Yes. Bird strike.
Can I get him in for runway 1?
Cactus 1549, you wanna
try and go to Teterboro?
Obstacle. Obstacle.
Pull up.
Clear of conflict.
"No relight after 30 seconds,
engine master one and two, confirm off."
Off.
"Wait 30 seconds."
Too low, terrain.
This is the captain.
Brace for impact.
Five hundred.
Cactus 1549, turn right 2-8-0.
You can land runway one Teterboro.
We can't make it.
Okay. Which runway
would you like at Teterboro?
Go ahead. Try number one.
Number one.
No relight.
We're gonna end up in the Hudson.
Too low, terrain.
I'm sorry. Say again, Cactus?
All right, let's put the flaps out.
Put the flaps out.
Flaps out.
Cactus 1549, radar contact lost.
You also got Newark off your two o'clock
in about seven miles.
Got flaps out.
Two hundred fifty feet in the air.
170 knots. Got no power on either one.
Try the other one.
1549? Still up?
One hundred and fifty knots.
- Got flaps two. You want more?
- No. Let's stay at two.
You got runway 2-9 available at Newark.
It'll be two o'clock in seven miles.
You got any ideas?
Actually not.
Terrain, terrain.
Pull up. Pull up.
Pull up.
We're gonna brace.
Thirty...
Twenty...
Pull up.
I need to take a quick break.
What did you think?
Hearing the CVR just now?
Let me tell you what I think.
I'm just so damn proud.
And you, you were right there,
through all that distraction.
With so much at stake.
We did this together. We were a team.
Thanks, Sully.
- We did our job.
Hey, you did good.
All right, folks.
I'd like to call this hearing
back to order.
If we could settle, please.
Take your seats.
That is honestly the first time
that I have listened to a crash recording
while actually sitting
with the captain and the first officer.
It's extraordinary.
That was no simulation.
No, it wasn't.
Gentlemen,
I want to inform you that
the left engine has been recovered.
We just received a comprehensive report.
There was extensive damage
to both the guide vanes
and fan blades of the engine.
Five compressor blades were fractured
and eight variable guide vanes missing.
So, no thrust?
As you testified,
it was completely destroyed.
The ACARS data was wrong.
I'd like to add something
on a personal note.
I can say with absolute confidence
that after speaking
with the rest of the flight crew,
with bird experts, aviation engineers,
after running through every scenario,
after interviewing each player,
there is still an "X" in this result
and it's you, Captain Sullenberger.
Remove you from the equation,
and the math just fails.
I disagree.
It wasn't just me. It was all of us.
It was Jeff and Donna
and Sheila and Doreen
and all of the passengers,
the rescue workers,
air traffic control,
ferry boat crews and the scuba cops.
We all did it.
We survived.
First Officer Skiles, is there
anything you'd like to add?
Anything you would have done differently
if you had to do it again?
Yes.
I would have done it in July.
7F. 11F.
9D.
1 C.
- 25B.
- 26B.
- 10B.
- 9A.
- 13C.
- 21A and B.
155 is a number,
but when you can put faces to it
and not just 155 faces,
but the other faces,
the wives, the daughters, the sons,
the fathers, the mothers, the brothers,
it gets to be a pretty big
number pretty quickly.
This is your captain speaking.
I think today was as much and as good
for me and my crew as it was for you.
And because of the events
of January 15, 2009,
I'm convinced that we will be joined
in our hearts and in our minds forever.
I am the keeper of the mail.
So I read when people
from across the country write to us.
And I open the letters
that come to our house from your families.
And I open the Christmas cards.
So, thank you so much
for the gratitude that you've
expressed to our families
and the letters and the cards
because they really do make
a difference to us as well.
So, thank you.
Provided by bozxphd
Modify by Blue-Bird™
(subscene.com/u/1191276)
Sync & corrections by Blue-Bird™